export const quizData = [
  {
    question:
      "In a Pushdown Automaton (PDA) with input symbols {𝑎,𝑏,𝑐} and stack symbols {𝑥,𝑦,𝑧,$} where $ represents the bottom of the stack, which transition correctly describes the action of popping 'y' from the stack?",
    options: {
      A: "𝛿(𝑞,𝑎,𝑦)=(p,ϵ)",
      B: "𝛿(𝑞,𝑏,𝑦)=(p,z)",
      C: "𝛿(𝑞,𝑐,𝑦)=(p,ϵ)",
      D: "𝛿(𝑞,𝜖,𝑦)=(p,ϵ)",
    },
    answer: "D",
  },
  {
    question:
      "How are finite automata classified based on their ability to remember past inputs?",
    options: {
      A: "Deterministic Finite Automata (DFA) and Non-Deterministic Finite Automata (NFA)",
      B: "Context-Free Grammars (CFG) and Context-Sensitive Grammars (CSG)",
      C: "Pushdown Automata (PDA) and Turing Machines (TM)",
      D: "Regular Expressions and Context-Free Languages",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the context of finite automata and formal languages, what does an alphabet represent?",
    options: {
      A: "A collection of states in the automaton.",
      B: "A set of symbols used to construct input strings.",
      C: "A set of transition rules between states.",
      D: "A set of final states in the automaton.",
    },
    answer: "B",
  },
  {
    question: "Which component(s) define the features of finite automata?",
    options: {
      A: "The input alphabet",
      B: "The set of states",
      C: "The transition function",
      D: "All of the above",
    },
    answer: "D",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What type of language is generated by a context-free grammar (CFG) in Chomsky Normal Form (CNF)?",
    options: {
      A: "Regular language",
      B: "Context-free language",
      C: "Context-sensitive language",
      D: "Recursive language",
    },
    answer: "B",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What type of language is recognized by a finite automaton with final states?",
    options: {
      A: "Regular language",
      B: "Context-free language",
      C: "Context-sensitive language",
      D: "Recursive language",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which type of automaton is suitable for recognizing Regular languages?",
    options: {
      A: "Deterministic Finite Automaton (DFA)",
      B: "Non-Deterministic Finite Automaton (NFA)",
      C: "Pushdown Automaton (PDA)",
      D: "Turing Machine (TM)",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a Pushdown Automaton (PDA) with states 𝑞0 and 𝑞1, input symbols {𝑎,𝑏}, and an initial transition from 𝑞0 to 𝑞1 with the empty stack, what are the possible transitions between 𝑞0 and 𝑞1?",
    options: {
      A: "{1,2,3,4}",
      B: "{1,2,3}",
      C: "{2,3,4}",
      D: "{1,2}",
    },
    answer: "B",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In Chomsky Normal Form (CNF), where do terminal symbols appear in production rules?",
    options: {
      A: "Terminals appear on the left-hand side of production rules.",
      B: "Terminals appear on the right-hand side of production rules.",
    },
    answer: "B",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In a Pushdown Automaton (PDA) with input symbols {0,1} and stack symbols {0,1,$}, which transition correctly pushes '0' onto the stack?",
    options: {
      A: "𝛿(𝑞,0,𝜖) = (q,0)",
      B: "𝛿(𝑞,1,𝜖) = (q,0)",
      C: "𝛿(𝑞,𝜖,0) = (q,0)",
      D: "𝛿(𝑞,0,$) = (q,0)",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What are the primary functions of the transition function in finite automata?",
    options: {
      A: "Determining the input alphabet and the set of states.",
      B: "Specifying the initial state and the set of accepting states.",
      C: "Handling non-determinism and ambiguity in state transitions.",
      D: "Determining the next state based on the current state and the input symbol being read.",
    },
    answer: "D",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which statement is true regarding the right-hand side (RHS) of production rules in Chomsky Normal Form (CNF) for context-free grammars?",
    options: {
      A: "The RHS can contain terminals only.",
      B: "The RHS can contain non-terminals only.",
      C: "The RHS can contain terminals and non-terminals in specific combinations.",
      D: "The RHS must contain at least one terminal and one non-terminal.",
    },
    answer: "C",
  },
  {
    question: "Which statement best describes a Finite Automaton (FA)?",
    options: {
      A: "A mathematical model consisting of a set of states, a set of input symbols, a transition function, and a set of accepting states, used for recognizing regular languages.",
      B: "A programming language construct used for looping and iteration in software development.",
      C: "A computational model capable of recognizing context-free languages and more complex patterns than regular languages.",
      D: "A type of data structure used for storing finite collections of elements, commonly implemented as an array or a linked list.",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not a characteristic of Chomsky Normal Form (CNF) for context-free grammars?",
    options: {
      A: "Nullable variable",
      B: "∈",
      C: "Start symbol appearing on the right-hand side of a production rule",
    },
    answer: "C",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the key difference between deterministic and non-deterministic finite automata?",
    options: {
      A: "Deterministic automata have multiple possible transitions for each input symbol.",
      B: "Non-deterministic automata cannot change states based on the input symbol.",
      C: "Deterministic automata have a single unique transition for each input symbol and state.",
      D: "Non-deterministic automata always halt after processing the input.",
    },
    answer: "C",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which statement best describes the non-terminal symbols allowed on the right-hand side (RHS) of production rules in Chomsky Normal Form (CNF) for context-free grammars?",
    options: {
      A: "Non-terminal symbols can only appear alone on the RHS.",
      B: "Non-terminal symbols can appear in pairs on the RHS.",
      C: "Non-terminal symbols cannot appear on the RHS in CNF.",
      D: "Non-terminal symbols can appear in pairs or alone on the RHS.",
    },
    answer: "B",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of the final state in a Finite Automaton (FA)?",
    options: {
      A: "The final state indicates the starting point of the automaton's computation.",
      B: "The final state determines the transitions between states based on the input symbols.",
      C: "The final state signifies the acceptance or rejection of an input string by the automaton.",
      D: "The final state represents the stack in a pushdown automaton.",
    },
    answer: "C",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the purpose of converting a context-free grammar into Chomsky Normal Form (CNF)?",
    options: {
      A: "To make it easier to parse the language generated by the grammar.",
      B: "To reduce the number of production rules in the grammar.",
      C: "To allow the use of regular expressions for pattern matching.",
      D: "To improve the efficiency of semantic analysis.",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What language is recognized by a Finite Automaton (FA) with a single final state?",
    options: {
      A: "The set of all strings that lead to the final state after processing the entire input string.",
      B: "The set of all strings that do not lead to the final state after processing the entire input string.",
      C: "The set of all strings composed of only terminal symbols.",
      D: "The set of all strings composed of both terminal and non-terminal symbols.",
    },
    answer: "A",
  },
  {
    question: "What functions of transition function in finite automata?",
    options: {
      A: "Determining the input alphabet and the set of states.",
      B: "Specifying the initial state and the set of accepting states.",
      C: "Handling non-determinism and ambiguity in state transitions.",
      D: "Determining the next state based on the current state and the input symbol being read.",
    },
    answer: "D",
  },
];